## STEPHEN BUSKIE

FINANCE | ENGINEERING | DATA

#### PERSONAL SUMMARY

Problem solver with world class engineering skillset. Experienced in influencing joint-ventures on billion dollar investments and c-suite executive reporting. Demonstrated ability to work effectively with multiple cultures through respect and communication while coordinating globally deployed teams for business planning purposes. Developer of digital solutions leveraging big data for global audiences.

- Houston, Texas | Internationally mobile stephenbuskie@gmail.com
  - https://sbuskie.github.io
- **(** +44 797 953 2368 | +1 832 616 7767

#### KEY SKILLS

- Management Information
- Leadership
- Business Intelligence
- Data Analytics and Visualisation
- Digital Twins
- Forecasting
- Stock Exchange Announcements
- Reporting and KPI Ownership
- Risk Management
- Scrum and Agile
- Investor Relations
- Coaching and Mentoring
- Finance and Audit
- Big Data

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Production Performance Lead bp, Finance (Houston, US)

January 2021 - Present

Squad lead for the production performance team, managing a multi-disciplinary team of 5 performance advisors and analysts. Successes include:

- Single point of accountability for bp's quarterly production reporting to the market; utilising SAP to build inputs to bp's quarterly results webcasts, stock exchange announcements, annual report and sustainability report. Led restated financial disclosures for bp's production aligned to 2021 restructuring.
- Lead for executive production reporting and management information during Group Performance Reviews, Operational Performance Reviews and Monthly Production Reviews. Streamlined weekly production reporting to CEO office.
- Managed coordination of bp's business planning for the production domain.
  Setup a community of practice (>50 participants) within teams across >15 geographies where bp operate, delivering value through consistency.

# Performance Analyst

May 2019 - December 2020

## bp, Finance (Houston, US)

Performance analyst responsible for the integrity, accuracy and timely delivery of management information related to bp's global Upstream hydrocarbon production (>2,500mboed). Highlights include:

- Development lead for digital business intelligence tools related to bp's production portfolio. Designed and deployed Microsoft Power BI reports globally (>200 users) facilitating improved business planning, quarterly variance commentary and executive weekly reporting.
- Collaborated with Palantir Technologies and bp data architects to connect SAP reported hydrocarbon production to the data lake, streamlining flow of carbon data to executive dashboards, quarterly external reports and bp's annual sustainability report eliminating data inconsistencies.
- Production subject matter expert aligning bp's production management workflows with the reinvented ambition to be net zero by 2050 or sooner, advising bp's Strategy and Sustainability team. Led the development of carbon as a production stream with equal importance to oil and gas production. Elicited improved and simplified carbon forecasting globally.
- Owned investor relations supplemental information for quarterly CFO and CEO investor calls; a team member of the "panel of experts" providing realtime support to the executives during investor calls.
- Additional c-suite responsibilities included risk management and reporting coordinator for bp's Reservoir Development (subsurface) function and supporting bp's quarterly appraisal table, part of bp's ~\$12-16bn/year capital allocation process; delivered to the Upstream COO.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Operating Systems | Windows, UNIX, Linux
- Data Visualisation | Excel, PowerBI,
  Spotfire, Streamlit
- Scripting Languages | Python, Bash
- Time-series Forecasting
- Microsoft 0365
- Microsoft PowerApps
- Azure Dev Ops
- SAP
- Applied Engineering | PETEX, Kappa
- Simulation Modelling | Nexus

#### HONOURS AND AWARDS

- Runner-up 2012 SET awards "Best Mechanical Engineering Student" undergraduate in Europe
- Masters degree sponsorship
- Institute of Mechanical Engineers individual project prize
- Undergraduate final year scholarship
- Deans merit list student each year of undergraduate studies

## Reservoir Engineer

#### December 2013 - April 2019

## bp, Reservoir Developments (Aberdeen, UK)

Managed complex reservoirs using both state of the art engineering practices (big data analytics, ensemble modelling and simulation modelling) and analytically from first principles. Applied pragmatic engineering practices to solve complex, multi-disciplinary, billion dollar problems. Experienced in all aspects of reservoir and petroleum engineering, creating digital twins of physical assets, with highlights including:

- Achieved approval of a 10-year facility life extension of a giant North Sea oil field. Previous teams were unsuccessful in gaining partner alignment for this project. Identified the triggers behind joint venture misalignment and constructed the project to resolve the issues. This added >80mmstb gross reserves and >\$350m value to the joint venture business in the reference case.
- Developed a digital twin of the Clair field and demonstrated an optimisation opportunity that was put into practice adding +\$20m revenue in one year.
- Managed 5 well drilling campaign from planning to safe delivery and coupled with multi-disciplinary debottlenecking activities improved Clair oil field operating efficiency by 20% and hydrocarbon production by 50%.
- Wrote python programme to automate post-processing of simulation model time-series forecasts for data visualisation, enabling analysis of >100 scenarios simultaneously using Tibco Spotfire.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Imperial College London, UK

2012-2013

#### Masters of Science in Petroleum Engineering, Distinction

Graduated with distinction. Attained full corporate sponsorship covering academic fees and living stipend. Attained World Education Service (WES) degree equivalency for USA and Canada.

## University of Strathclyde, UK

2008-2012

## Bachelors of Mechanical Engineering with Honours, First Class

Runner-up of the European Science, Engineering and Technology (SET) awards, in the 'Best Mechanical Engineering Student' category as judged by the Institute of Mechanical Engineers. The SET Awards provide a showcase for educational excellence by publicly recognising the exceptional achievements of both students and universities. They are Europe's most high profile event for science, engineering and technology undergraduates.

Awarded the University of Strathclyde Institute of Mechanical Engineers individual project prize. Additionally awarded final year scholarship based on demonstrated academic record.